List<questions> comQuestions = [
  questions(
      question: "Which is the largest commercial Bank of India",
      a: "PNB",
      b: "SBI",
      c: "UCO",
      d: "BOB",
      answer: "SBI"),
  questions(
      question: "Full form of YONO",
      a: "You only need one",
      b: "You only new one",
      c: "You observe new one",
      d: "You observe need one",
      answer: "You only need one")
];

// normal questions
List<questions> normalQuestions = [
  questions(
      question: "Who was the first woman Governor of India",
      a: "Indira Gandhi ",
      b: "Draupadi Murmu",
      c: "Sarojini Naidu",
      d: "Pratibha Patil ",
      answer: "Sarojini Naidu"),
  questions(
      question: "Who is the grandfather of India?",
      a: "Mahatma Gandhi",
      b: "Draupadi Murmu",
      c: "Maharshi Dyanand Sarswati",
      d: "Dr. B. R. Ambedkar",
      answer: "Maharshi Dyanand Sarswati"),
  questions(
      question: "How many SBILD are there in SBI?",
      a: "40",
      b: "45",
      c: "50",
      d: "52",
      answer: "50"),
  questions(
      question:
          "To facilitate to medical treatment for Covid 19 SBI launched which personal loan?",
      a: "Kavach Loan",
      b: "Chikistya Loan",
      c: "Get well soon Plan",
      d: "Ayshman Bharat Loan",
      answer: "Kavach Loan"),
  questions(
      question:
          "Ajay Banga was selected as the President of the World Bank group and began his term on June 2, 2023.What is the incumbency of his present position in the World Bank group?",
      a: "14",
      b: "13",
      c: "15",
      d: "16",
      answer: "14"),
  questions(
      question:
          "How many languages are there in the 500 rupees paper currency note in India including the panel?",
      a: "16",
      b: "15",
      c: "18",
      d: "17",
      answer: "17"),
  questions(
      question:
          "Which monument is printed in one side of 20 rupee currency note?",
      a: "Red fort",
      b: "Ellora Caves",
      c: "Rani ki Vav",
      d: "Hampi Temple",
      answer: "Ellora Caves"),
  questions(
      question:
          "What is the present position as per the incumbency of the CGM of the Kolkata Circle?",
      a: "24",
      b: "25",
      c: "26",
      d: "27",
      answer: "26"),
  questions(
      question: "From which date SBI started using the keyhole logo?",
      a: "October 1, 1971",
      b: "July 1, 1955",
      c: "July 1, 1971",
      d: "July 1, 1969",
      answer: "October 1, 1971"),
  questions(
      question: "From which date SBI started using the keyhole logo?",
      a: "October 1, 1971",
      b: "July 1, 1955",
      c: "July 1, 1971",
      d: "July 1, 1969",
      answer: "October 1, 1971"),
  questions(
      question:
          "Bank of Calcutta, from its inception, has been assigned with the power to issue [currency] Notes. But which was the first Bank in India to issue these Notes?",
      a: "Asiatic Bank",
      b: "Bank of Hindostan",
      c: "Madras Bank",
      d: "Bank of Calcutta",
      answer: "Bank of Hindostan"),
  questions(
      question:
          "After the passage of the Indian Currency Act, 1861, where was the first-ever Branch of any Presidency Bank opened?",
      a: "Dacca",
      b: "Mirzapur",
      c: "Pune",
      d: "Rangoon",
      answer: "Rangoon"),
  questions(
      question:
          "Who was the first free India’s Minister of Railways and later the Minister of Finance?",
      a: "1903",
      b: "1902",
      c: "1905",
      d: "1901",
      answer: "1902"),
  questions(
      question: "When was the Savings Bank Deposit Scheme introduced?",
      a: "C D Deshmukh",
      b: "John Matthai",
      c: "B R Ambedkar",
      d: "Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel",
      answer: "John Matthai"),
  questions(
      question:
          "Who was the first Indian Secretary &  Treasurer of the Imperial Bank of India?",
      a: "P.A. Engineer",
      b: "JRD Tata",
      c: "S K Handoo",
      d: "John Matthai",
      answer: "P.A. Engineer"),
  questions(
      question:
          "From which year onwards the balance sheet of the SBI changed from calendar year to financial year?",
      a: "1986",
      b: "1987",
      c: "1988",
      d: "1990",
      answer: "1988"),
  questions(
      question:
          "Online, SBI the banks’ internet banking rolled out on a pilot basis in which year?",
      a: "August 1, 2000",
      b: "August 1, 2001",
      c: "August 1, 2002",
      d: "August 15, 2003",
      answer: "August 1, 2000"),
  questions(
      question:
          "Bank’s Day is celebrated on July 1. What other’s celebrated on that day?",
      a: "Martyr’s Day",
      b: "Mother’s Day",
      c: "Human Rights Day",
      d: "Doctors Day",
      answer: "Doctors Day"),
  questions(
      question: "What is the helpline number for financial fraud in India?",
      a: "1930",
      b: "1906",
      c: "1363",
      d: "1098",
      answer: "1930"),
  questions(
      question:
          "Who has designed the SBI Key hole logo which was replaced by the banyan tree logo?",
      a: "R K Talwar",
      b: "John Matthai",
      c: "Shekhar Kamat",
      d: "Indira Gandhi",
      answer: "Shekhar Kamat"),
  questions(
      question: "First talkie film of India",
      a: "Raja Harishchandra",
      b: "Alam Ara",
      c: "Kishan Kanheiya",
      d: "Sadma",
      answer: "Alam Ara"),
  questions(
      question: "‘Play it my way’ written by whom",
      a: "Sachin Tendulkar",
      b: "Ravi Shatri",
      c: "Sunil Gavaskar",
      d: "Rahul Dravid",
      answer: "Sachin Tendulkar"),
  questions(
      question:
          "Who won the Dada Saheb Phalke Award for the life time achievement in 2023?",
      a: "Waheeda Rahman",
      b: "Asha Parekh",
      c: "Tanuja",
      d: "Farida Jala",
      answer: "Waheeda Rahman"),
  questions(
      question:
          "Who won the Dada Saheb Phalke Award for the life time achievement in 2023?",
      a: "Waheeda Rahman",
      b: "Asha Parekh",
      c: "Tanuja",
      d: "Farida Jala",
      answer: "Waheeda Rahman"),
  questions(
      question:
          "In 1878 which bank was first to introduce the Pension & Guarantee Fund?",
      a: "Bank of Calcutta",
      b: "Bank of Bombay",
      c: "Bank of Bengal",
      d: "Bank of Madras",
      answer: "Bank of Madras"),
  questions(
      question:
          "To facilitate the spread of Banking facilities the Imperial Bank of India in 1921 as agreed with the Government of India to open how many numbers of new branches within the first five years.",
      a: "50",
      b: "75",
      c: "100",
      d: "150",
      answer: "100"),
  questions(
      question: "When the foreign exchange department was set up in Calcutta?",
      a: "1932",
      b: "1937",
      c: "1935",
      d: "1947",
      answer: "1937"),
  questions(
      question: "The computers were first introduced in SBI in which year?",
      a: "1966",
      b: "1967",
      c: "1971",
      d: "1970",
      answer: "1967"),
  questions(
      question:
          "Till August 1947, Imperial Bank has opened how many branches in Pakistan?",
      a: "23",
      b: "24",
      c: "25",
      d: "26",
      answer: "23"),
  questions(
      question:
          "From which year onwards the post of Managing Directors in SBI was increased from two to four?",
      a: "2011",
      b: "2019",
      c: "2012",
      d: "2010",
      answer: "2010"),
  questions(
      question: "What does the dark blue color in the SBI Logo represent?",
      a: "Unity & prosperity",
      b: "Trust & integrity",
      c: "Security & safety",
      d: "Security & Trust",
      answer: "Trust & integrity"),
  questions(
      question: "What is the majorly used Toll-Free number of SBI?",
      a: "18004321/18002100",
      b: "18003800/18001234",
      c: "18001234/18002100",
      d: "18001234/18002211",
      answer: "18001234/18002100"),
  questions(
      question:
          "When did associates bank become subsidiaries of the State Bank of India?",
      a: "1955",
      b: "1959",
      c: "1969",
      d: "1961",
      answer: "1959"),
  questions(
      question:
          "Year of printing on rupees 200 notes is written in which part of the note?",
      a: "Right in front",
      b: "Right of reverse",
      c: "Left in reverse",
      d: "Middle in reverse",
      answer: "Left in reverse"),
  questions(
      question:
          "In which year RBI transfer its entire Share holding in SBI to the Government of India?",
      a: "2001",
      b: "2005",
      c: "2009",
      d: "2007",
      answer: "2007"),
  questions(
      question: "What is the title of the Annual Report for the year 2022-23?",
      a: "Progress & prospects",
      b: "Achievement & Challenges",
      c: "Year in Review",
      d: "Responsive Responsible Resilient",
      answer: "Responsive Responsible Resilient"),
  questions(
      question: "What is the common seal of the SBI?",
      a: "Banyan tree",
      b: "Key whole logo",
      c: "Bankers to every Indian",
      d: "Be Safe Go Yono",
      answer: "Banyan tree"),
  questions(
      question: "Employee engagement survey 2023 is called",
      a: "Saksham",
      b: "Parivartan",
      c: "SBI Citizen",
      d: "Abhiuday",
      answer: "Abhiuday"),
  questions(
      question:
          "Which institution developed India’s first ‘Farmland Price Index’?",
      a: "IIT Kharagpur",
      b: "IIT Mumbai",
      c: "IIT Madras",
      d: "IIT Delhi",
      answer: "IIT Madras"),
  questions(
      question:
          "Pension departemtn has recently launched an online portal for government retirees? What is the name of the portal?",
      a: "Abhyukt Portal",
      b: "Vriddhi Portal",
      c: "Bhavishya Portal",
      d: "Vikas Portal",
      answer: "Bhavishya Portal"),
  questions(
      question:
          "Recently, which country won the gold medal in the Archery World Cup in the Mens recurve events?",
      a: "India",
      b: "South Korea",
      c: "Malaysia",
      d: "Indonesia",
      answer: "India"),
  questions(
      question:
          "Tale Valley wild life sanctuary, recently seen in news, is located in which state?",
      a: "Arunachal Pradesh",
      b: "Assam",
      c: "Maharashtra",
      d: "Tamil Nadu",
      answer: "Arunachal Pradesh"),
  questions(
      question: "When is the National Voters Day celebrated in India?",
      a: "5 January",
      b: "5 December",
      c: "25 January",
      d: "25 December",
      answer: "25 January"),
  questions(
      question: "Which is the third highest civilian award in India?",
      a: "Bharat Ratna",
      b: "Padma Bhushan",
      c: "Padma Shri",
      d: "Padma Vibhushan",
      answer: "Padma Bhushan"),
  questions(
      question: "When is the National Voters Day celebrated in India?",
      a: "5 January",
      b: "5 December",
      c: "25 January",
      d: "25 December",
      answer: "25 January"),
  questions(
      question: "Who was the first Governor of the Reserve Bank of India?",
      a: "Osborne A Smith",
      b: "Robert Aitken",
      c: "William Lamond",
      d: "C D Deshmukh",
      answer: "Osborne A Smith"),
  questions(
      question: "When was the Reserve Bank of India nationalised",
      a: "1-Jan-35",
      b: "1-Apr-35",
      c: "1-Jan-49",
      d: "1-Jan-49",
      answer: "1-Jan-49"),
  questions(
      question: "At which place does the Hooghly river enters in Bengal?",
      a: "Maldah",
      b: "Farakka",
      c: "Murshidabad",
      d: "Hugli",
      answer: "Murshidabad"),
  questions(
      question: "Who is the founder of Brahmo Samaj?",
      a: "Rajaram Mohan Roy",
      b: "Dadabhai Naroji",
      c: "Aurbindo",
      d: "Suryasen",
      answer: "Rajaram Mohan Roy"),
  questions(
      question:
          "Which social reformer of Bengal worked tirelessly for widow marriage, primarily?",
      a: "Rajaram Mohan Roy",
      b: "Ishwarchand Vidyasagar",
      c: "Vivekanand",
      d: "kamini Devi",
      answer: "IshwarChand Vidyasagar"),
  questions(
      question: "Where did the famous social reformer Raja Ram Mohan Roy die?",
      a: "Kolkata",
      b: "London",
      c: "Paris",
      d: "Delhi",
      answer: "London"),
  questions(
      question: "Who wrote 'New Lamps for Old?",
      a: "Rajaram Mohan Roy",
      b: "Dadabhai Naroji",
      c: "Aurbindo",
      d: "Suryasen",
      answer: "Aurbindo"),
  questions(
      question: "Who is associated with the concept of 'Navvedanta'?",
      a: "Rajaram Mohan Roy",
      b: "Ishwarchand Vidyasagar",
      c: "Vivekanand",
      d: "Lala Lajpat Rai",
      answer: "Vivekanand"),
  questions(
      question: "Who started the Kirtan in Bhakti Movement?",
      a: "Vivekanand",
      b: "Chaitanya Mahaprabhu",
      c: "Aurbindo",
      d: "Gopla Krishan Gokhale",
      answer: "Chaitanya Mahaprabhu"),
  questions(
      question: "When was  founder of VISHWA BHARTI ?",
      a: "Gopal Krishan Gokhale",
      b: "Dadabhai Naroji",
      c: "Bal Gangadhar Tilak",
      d: "Ravindranath Tagore",
      answer: "Ravindranath Tagore"),
  questions(
      question: "When was founder of Ramakrishna Mission ?",
      a: "Rajaram Mohan Roy",
      b: "Ishwarchand Vidyasagar",
      c: "Vivekanand",
      d: "Lala Lajpat Rai",
      answer: "1897"),
  questions(
      question: "Founder of Kolkata",
      a: "Wellesely",
      b: "job charnock",
      c: "Curzon",
      d: "Lyton",
      answer: "job charnock"),
  questions(
      question: "Digha Sea Beach in which District?",
      a: "Dakshin Medinipur",
      b: "Purba Medinipur",
      c: "Paschim Medinipur",
      d: "Uttar Medinipur",
      answer: "Purba Medinipur"),
  questions(
      question: "The world's most treacherous river",
      a: "Ganga",
      b: "Hugli",
      c: "Yamuna",
      d: "Saraswati",
      answer: "Hughli"),
  questions(
      question: "Who is the father of Nation?",
      a: "Gurudev",
      b: "Satyendra Bose",
      c: "Mahatma Gandhi",
      d: "Rajaram Mohan Roy",
      answer: "Mahatma Gandhi"),
  questions(
      question: "Who is the first President of India?",
      a: "Rajendra Prasad",
      b: "APJ Abdul Kalam",
      c: "Droupadi Murmu",
      d: "Ram Nath Kovind",
      answer: "Rajendra Prasad"),
  questions(
      question: "Where was Singalia National Park is ",
      a: "Siliguri",
      b: "Darjeeling",
      c: "Nepal",
      d: "Murshidabad",
      answer: "Darjeeling"),
  questions(
      question: "Toto' tribal in which state",
      a: "Tamilnadu",
      b: "Andhra Pradesh",
      c: "West Bengal",
      d: "Jharkhand",
      answer: "West Bengal"),
  questions(
      question: "Who is known as Father of Indian constitution",
      a: "Sardar vallabhbhai Patel",
      b: "Dr Rajendra Prasad",
      c: "Mahatma Gandhi",
      d: "Dr B R Ambedkar",
      answer: "Dr B R Ambedkar"),
  questions(
      question: "Metro Rail is started in Kolkata",
      a: "1984",
      b: "1986",
      c: "1988",
      d: "1989",
      answer: "1984"),
  questions(
      question: "Who was the first Prime Minister of India?",
      a: "Gopal Krishan Gokhale",
      b: "Jawaharlal Nehru",
      c: "Bal Gangadhar Tilak",
      d: "Ravindranath Tagore",
      answer: "Jawaharlal Nehru"),
  questions(
      question: "Known as-'Doors towards Bhutan'",
      a: "Siliguri",
      b: "Banarhat",
      c: "Darjiling",
      d: "Jalpaiguri",
      answer: "Jalpaiguri"),
  questions(
      question: "Which one is of the highest length",
      a: "Teesta",
      b: "Mahananda",
      c: "Jaldhaka",
      d: "Jalangai",
      answer: "Teesta"),
  questions(
      question: "India lies in which continent?",
      a: "Africa",
      b: "Antarctica",
      c: "Asia",
      d: "North America",
      answer: "Asia"),
  questions(
      question: "How many Cricket world cup does India have?",
      a: "4",
      b: "3",
      c: "2",
      d: "1",
      answer: "2"),
  questions(
      question: "'CANADA DAM' is associated with which project",
      a: "Mayurakshi",
      b: "Damodar",
      c: "Kansabati",
      d: "Jaldhaka",
      answer: "Mayurakshi"),
  questions(
      question: "First Jute mill in India",
      a: "Naihati",
      b: "Serampore",
      c: "Kulti",
      d: "Rishra",
      answer: "Rishra"),
  questions(
      question: "Durgapur Steel Plant was set up in collaboration with:",
      a: "Russia",
      b: "Germany",
      c: "Britain",
      d: "France",
      answer: "Britain"),
  questions(
      question: "Smallest State in India?",
      a: "Sikkim",
      b: "Goa",
      c: "UP",
      d: "MP",
      answer: "Goa"),
  questions(
      question: "Who was the inspiration behind'YOUNG BANGAL MOVEMENT'",
      a: "Madhusudan Datta",
      b: "Derozio",
      c: "Ramgopal ghosh",
      d: "Rammohan Roy",
      answer: "Derozio"),
  questions(
      question: "National Tree of India ?",
      a: "Pipal",
      b: "Banyan",
      c: "Banana",
      d: "Teak",
      answer: "Banyan"),
  questions(
      question: "Akbar of Bangal",
      a: "Pratapaditya",
      b: "Ilyaas Shah",
      c: "Sirajuddaula",
      d: "Hussain Shah",
      answer: "Hussain Sah"),
  questions(
      question: "Ashutosh is another name of ",
      a: "Shiv",
      b: "Ganga",
      c: "Vishnu",
      d: "Ganesh",
      answer: "Shiv"),
  questions(
      question: "Vishnupur Mela in which district",
      a: "Harimohanpur",
      b: "Darjiling",
      c: "Bolpur",
      d: "Bankura",
      answer: "Bankura"),
  questions(
      question: "Who has given the name 'MAHATMA' to Gandhi",
      a: "Rajaram Mohan Roy",
      b: "Ishwarchand Vidyasagar",
      c: "Vivekanand",
      d: "Ravindranath Thakur",
      answer: "Ravindranath Thakur"),
  questions(
      question: "Kolkata is the first city to have a ______",
      a: "Metro",
      b: "Bus",
      c: "Tram ",
      d: "All of these ",
      answer: "Metro"),
  questions(
      question: "In West Bengal, the first railway station was erected at",
      a: "Chandan nagar",
      b: "Howrah Railway Junction Station",
      c: "Chinsurah",
      d: "Sealdah",
      answer: "Howrah Railway Junction Station"),
  questions(
      question: "Which country’s size is equivalent to West Bengal’s?",
      a: "Serbia ",
      b: "Australia ",
      c: "NewZee Land",
      d: "Srilanka ",
      answer: "Srilanka "),
  questions(
      question:
          "After West Bengal became an Indian state, who was the first Chief Minister of the state?",
      a: "Siddhartha Shankar Ray",
      b: "Prafulla Chandra Sen",
      c: "Ajoy Mukherjee",
      d: "Bidhan Chandra Roy",
      answer: "Bidhan Chandra Roy"),
  questions(
      question:
          "What is West Bengal’s position on India’s list of largest states by area?",
      a: "14th ",
      b: "13th ",
      c: "15th ",
      d: "16th ",
      answer: "14th "),
  questions(
      question: "What is the most sensitive organ of our body?",
      a: "Skin",
      b: "Eye",
      c: "Nose",
      d: "Ear",
      answer: "Skin"),
  questions(
      question: "Giddha is the folk dance of",
      a: "Uttar Pradesh",
      b: "Punjab",
      c: "Jharkhand",
      d: "Odisha",
      answer: "Punjab"),
  questions(
      question: "Who invented computer?",
      a: "Sundar Pichai",
      b: "Bill Gates",
      c: "Satya Nadella",
      d: "Charles Babbage",
      answer: "Charles Babbage"),
  questions(
      question: "How many dots appears on a pair of dice?",
      a: "21",
      b: "42",
      c: "36",
      d: "54",
      answer: "42"),
  questions(
      question: "What is the only body part that is fully grown from birth?",
      a: "Eyeball",
      b: "Skin",
      c: "Eye",
      d: "Nose",
      answer: "Eyeball"),
  questions(
      question: "In which country was Elon Musk born?",
      a: "America",
      b: "UK",
      c: "South Africa",
      d: "Canada",
      answer: "South Africa"),
  questions(
      question: "Who is the host of KBC?",
      a: "Amitabh Bachchan",
      b: "Amir Khan",
      c: "Shahrukh Khan",
      d: "Virat Kohli",
      answer: "Amitabh Bachchan"),
  questions(
      question: "Who is the first Indian to win a Nobel prize?",
      a: "Jagadish Ch. Bose",
      b: "Rabindranath Tagore",
      c: "Amartya Sen",
      d: "Mother Teresa",
      answer: "Rabindranath Tagore"),
  questions(
      question: "Who heads RBI?",
      a: "Dinesh Khara",
      b: "Shaktikanta Das",
      c: "Raghuram Rajan",
      d: "Urijit Patel",
      answer: "Shaktikanta Das"),
  questions(
      question: "Durand cup is associated with which game?",
      a: "Hockey",
      b: "Cricket",
      c: "Football",
      d: "Basketball",
      answer: "Football"),
  questions(
      question: "Present brand ambassador of SBI?",
      a: "M S Dhoni",
      b: "Virat Kohli",
      c: "Amitabh Bachhan",
      d: "Shah Rukh Khan",
      answer: "M S Dhoni"),
  questions(
      question: "Hemis National Park is located at",
      a: "Jammu & Kashmir",
      b: "Uttarakhand",
      c: "Rajasthan",
      d: "Himachal Pradesh",
      answer: "Jammu & Kashmir"),
  questions(
      question: "Kolkata international Book Fair Started in which year?",
      a: "1975",
      b: "1976",
      c: "1977",
      d: "1978",
      answer: "1976"),
  questions(
      question: "International women’s day",
      a: "8 January",
      b: "8 February",
      c: "8 March",
      d: "9 March",
      answer: "8 March"),
  questions(
      question: "Biggest waterfall in India located in which state?",
      a: "Karnataka",
      b: "Tamilnadu",
      c: "Kerala",
      d: "Shillong",
      answer: "Karnataka"),
  questions(
      question: "Largest river Basin in India ",
      a: "Godavari",
      b: "Ganga",
      c: "Mahanadi",
      d: "Sutlej",
      answer: "Ganga"),
  questions(
      question: "Bhitarkanika national park is located at which state?",
      a: "Odisha",
      b: "West Bengal",
      c: "Jharkhand",
      d: "Bihar",
      answer: "Odisha"),
  questions(
      question: "Bangladesh was formed in which year?",
      a: "1973",
      b: "1972",
      c: "1970",
      d: "1971",
      answer: "1971"),
  questions(
      question: "Who is the Grand old man of India?",
      a: "Dadabhai Naoroji",
      b: "Jawaharlal Nehru",
      c: "Sardar Ballav Bhai Patel",
      d: "Mahatma Gandhi",
      answer: "Dadabhai Naoroji"),
  questions(
      question:
          "In which Indian State is Chauri Chaura village is located in state?",
      a: "Bihar",
      b: "Odisha",
      c: "Uttar Pradesh",
      d: "Jharkhand",
      answer: "Uttar Pradesh"),
];

class questions {
  String? question;
  String? a;
  String? b;
  String? c;
  String? d;
  String? answer;
  questions({this.question, this.a, this.b, this.c, this.d, this.answer});
}
